Daniel C. Dennett Papers MS138
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Writings, 1958 -- 2015; MS138.001; 4.15 Linear Feet; 415 Digital Object(s)
  - A Daring Reconnaissance of Red Territory: A Review of Seeing Red: A Study in Consciousness, by Nicholas Humphrey, 2007; MS138.001.003.00062; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - A Daring Reconnaissance of Red Territory: A Review of Seeing Red: A Study in Consciousness, by Nicholas Humphrey, 2007; MS138.001.003.00062.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - An Unlovable Puddle: Letter to the Editor, 2007; MS138.001.003.00063; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Open Letter to H. Allen Orr, 2007; MS138.001.003.00064; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Introduction, 2007; MS138.001.003.00065; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - The Evaporation of the Powerful Mystique of Religion, 2007; MS138.001.003.00066; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Philosophy as Naive Anthropology: Comment on Bennett and Hacker, 2007; MS138.001.003.00067; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
    Philosophy; Cognitive neuroscience; Conciousness; Mereology; A priori; Bennet, M.R.; Hacker, P.M.S.; Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1889-1951.
  - My Body Has a Mind of Its Own, MS138.001.003.00068; Dennett, Daniel C.
    PLACEHOLDER RECORD
  - Letter to the Editor: Response to Jerry Fodor, 2007; MS138.001.003.00069; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Off Come The Gloves: Review of The God Delusion, by Richard Dawkins, 2007; MS138.001.003.00070; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
    Atheism; Science; Public Opinion; Religion; Dawkins, Richard, 1941-
  - Atheism and Evolution, 2007; MS138.001.003.00071; Dennett, Daniel C.
    Intelligent design; Teleology; Atheism; Natural selection; Complexity, Biological
  - Letter to the Editor: A Response to H. Allen Orr's Review of The God Delusion, by Richard Dawkins, 2007; MS138.001.003.00072; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Heterophenomenology Reconsidered, 2006 -- 2007; MS138.001.003.00073; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Heterophenomenology Reconsidered, 2006; MS138.001.003.00073.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Heterophenomenology Reconsidered, 2007; MS138.001.003.00073.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Instead of a Review: A Review of I am a Strange Loop, by Douglas Hofstadter and The Emotion Machine, by Marvin Minsky, 2007; MS138.001.003.00074; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Instead of a Review: A Review of I am a Strange Loop, by Douglas Hofstadter and The Emotion Machine, by Marvin Minsky, 2007; MS138.001.003.00074.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Instead of a Review: A Review of I am a Strange Loop, by Douglas Hofstadter and The Emotion Machine, by Marvin Minsky, 2007; MS138.001.003.00074.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Unbelievable: A Review of God Is Not Great: How Religion Poisons Everything, by Christopher Hitchens, 2007; MS138.001.003.00075; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - McGill University, 2007 Commencement Address, MS138.001.003.00076; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Can Outrage in Afghanistan Inspire Us?: Letter to the Editor, 2008; MS138.001.003.00077; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Can Outrage in Afghanistan Inspire Us?: Letter to the Editor, 2008; MS138.001.003.00077.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Can Outrage in Afghanistan Inspire Us?: Letter to the Editor, 2008; MS138.001.003.00077.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Whole-Body Apoptosis, 2008; MS138.001.003.00078; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Astride the Two Cultures: A Letter to Richard Powers, Updated, 2003; MS138.001.003.00079; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Autobiographical Essay, Part 1, 2008; MS138.001.003.00080; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Autobiographical Essay, Part 2, 2008; MS138.001.003.00081; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Autobiographical Essay, Part 3, 2008; MS138.001.003.00082; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Descartes's Argument from Design, 2008; MS138.001.003.00083; Dennett, Daniel C.; McKay, Ryan
    - Descartes's Argument from Design, 2008-07; MS138.001.003.00083.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
      Metaphysics; Intelligent design; Descartes, René, 1596-1650
    - Descartes's Argument from Design, 2008; MS138.001.003.00083.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - How to Protect Human Dignity from Science, 2008; MS138.001.003.00084; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Fun and Games in Fantasyland, 2008; MS138.001.003.00085; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Fun and Games in Fantasyland, 2008; MS138.001.003.00085.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Fun and Games in Fantasyland, 2008; MS138.001.003.00085.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Commentary on Kraynak, 2008; MS138.001.003.00086; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Commentary on Kraynak, 2008; MS138.001.003.00086.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Commentary on Kraynak, 2008; MS138.001.003.00086.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Some Observations on the Psychology of Thinking about Free Will, 2007 -- 2008; MS138.001.003.00087; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Some Observations on the Psychology of Thinking about Free Will, 2007; MS138.001.003.00087.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Some Observations on the Psychology of Thinking about Free Will, 2008; MS138.001.003.00087.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Competition in the Brain, 2009; MS138.001.003.00088; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Heterophenomenology, 2009; MS138.001.003.00089; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Multiple Drafts Model, 2009; MS138.001.003.00090; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Intentional Systems Theory, 2009; MS138.001.003.00091; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Review of The Really Hard Problem: Meaning in a Material World, Owen Flanagan, 2009; MS138.001.003.00092; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Richard Dawkins: Biographical Essay, 2009; MS138.001.003.00093; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Evolution of 'Why?', 2006 -- 2010; MS138.001.003.00094; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - The Evolution of 'Why?', 2006; MS138.001.003.00094.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - The Evolution of 'Why?', 2010; MS138.001.003.00094.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Verbal Language as a Communicative System, 1992 -- 1999; MS138.001.003.00095; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Verbal Language as a Communicative System, 1992; MS138.001.003.00095.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
    - Bahasa Verbal sebagai Sistem Komunikatif [Malay translation of Verbal Language as a Communicative System], 1999; MS138.001.003.00095.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Kinds of Minds, 1996 -- 2006; MS138.001.003.00096; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Micsoda Elmék: A Tudatosság megértése felé [Hungarian translation of Kinds of Minds], 1996; MS138.001.003.00096.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - Tiops de Mentes: Rumo a uma compreensão da consciência [Portuguese translation of Kinds of Minds], 1997; MS138.001.003.00096.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - Natura Umysɫów [Polish translation of Kinds of Minds], 1997; MS138.001.003.00096.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - [Chinese translation of Kinds of Minds], 1997; MS138.001.003.00096.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - La Diversité des esprits: Une Approche de la conscience [French translation of Kinds of Minds], 1998; MS138.001.003.00096.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - Spielarten des Geistes [German translation of Kinds of Minds], 1999; MS138.001.003.00096.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - [Hebrew translation of Kinds of Minds], 1999; MS138.001.003.00096.00007; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - La Mente e le Menti: Verso una comprensione della coscienza [Italian translation of Kinds of Minds], 1999; MS138.001.003.00096.00008; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - [Korean translation of Kinds of Minds], 2006; MS138.001.003.00096.00009; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - [Korean translation of Kinds of Minds], 2006; MS138.001.003.00096.00010; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
  - Dennett versus Rorty, 1999; MS138.001.003.00097; Dennett, Daniel C.; Yulina, N.S. (Box 3)
  - Zum Schutz der wissenschaftlichen Untersuchung des Bewutseins vor ideologischen Debatten, 2003; MS138.001.003.00098; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Higher Order Truths About Chmess, 2006; MS138.001.003.00099; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Pastor's Secret: What happens when preachers don't believe, 2010; MS138.001.003.00100; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Homunculi Rule: Reflections on Darwinian Populations and Natural Selection (Oxford University Press, 2009) by Peter Godfrey Smith, 2010; MS138.001.003.00101; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Skoal, 1958; MS138.001.003.00102; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Making Cider Wine, 1974 -- 1975; MS138.001.003.00103; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Dennett's Dangerous Idea, 1996; MS138.001.003.00104; Beardsley, Tim (Box 3)
  - What is the Soul?, 1997; MS138.001.003.00105; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Wer ist hier der Ultra-Darwinist?, 1998; MS138.001.003.00106; Dennett, Daniel C.; Rose, Steven (Box 3)
  - An Interview with Daniel Dennett, 2002; MS138.001.003.00107; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Is religion a threat to rationality and science? Yes, 2008; MS138.001.003.00108; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett, 2009; MS138.001.003.00109; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
    Made available with permission of Automatic Press/VIP.
  - The Fact of Evolution, 2009; MS138.001.003.00110; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Introduction to This Will Change Everything, 2010; MS138.001.003.00111; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Thank goodness for Dan, 2010; MS138.001.003.00112; Baggini, Julian (Box 3)
  - Preachers Who Are Not Believers, 2010; MS138.001.003.00113; Dennett, Daniel C.; LaScola, Linda (Box 3)
  - The heir of Bertrand Russell / El heredero de Bertrand Russell, 2010; MS138.001.003.00114; Marotti, Mario (Box 3)
  - The unbelievers: What happens when a minister decides there's no God?, 2010; MS138.001.003.00115; Bennett, Drake; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Evolution of "Why?", 2010; MS138.001.003.00116; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett: The philosophical rabblerouser recharges his mind at SFI, 2010; MS138.001.003.00117; Jackson, Devon (Box 3)
  - Foreword to The Company of Strangers, 2010; MS138.001.003.00118; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Priests Who Don't Believe, 2010; MS138.001.003.00119; Dennett, Daniel C.; LaScola, Linda (Box 3)
  - Serbian translation of From Typo to Thinko: When Evolution Graduated to Semantic Norms, 2010; MS138.001.003.00120; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Unbelievable Truth: Why America has become a nation of religious know-nothings, 2010; MS138.001.003.00121; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Multi-use and constraints from original use, 2010; MS138.001.003.00122; Dennett, Daniel C.; Justin A. Jungé (Box 3)
  - Evolutionary Philosophy, 2010; MS138.001.003.00123; Dennett, Daniel C.; Wilson, Edward O. (Box 3)
  - The Pastor's Secret: What happens when preachers don't believe?, 2010; MS138.001.003.00124; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Magia Odczarowana, 2010; MS138.001.003.00125; Jalochowski, Karol; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Who's Still Afraid of Determinism? Rethinking Causes and Possibilities, 2010; MS138.001.003.00126; Taylor, Christopher; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - We Earth Neurons, 1999 -- 2010; MS138.001.003.00127; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Truths That Miss Their Mark: Naturalism Unscathed / Habits of Imagination and Their Effect on Incredulity: Reply to Plantinga / No Miracles Needed, 2011; MS138.001.003.00128; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Power Corrupts, 2011; MS138.001.003.00129; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - "My Brain Made Me Do It" (When Neuroscientists Think They Can Do Philosophy), 2011; MS138.001.003.00130; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Cuerpo íntegro-Apoptosis 1.0: Por una muerte celular programada, 2011; MS138.001.003.00131; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - 9/11 confirmed worst fears about religion, 2011; MS138.001.003.00132; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Consciousness cannot be separated from function, 2011; MS138.001.003.00133; Cohen, Michael A.; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Shall we tango? No, but thanks for asking, 2011; MS138.001.003.00134; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - An answer to the question "Why don't you believe in God?", 2011; MS138.001.003.00135; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Turing's "Strange Inversion of Reasoning", 2011 -- 2013; MS138.001.003.00136; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - A Lesson from Hitch: When Rudeness is Called for, 2011; MS138.001.003.00137; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The social cell: What do debutante balls, the Japanese tea ceremony, Ponzi schemes and doubting clergy all have in common?, 2011; MS138.001.003.00138; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Quine in my life, 2011; MS138.001.003.00139; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Whole-Body Apoptosis and the Meanings of Lives, 2011; MS138.001.003.00140; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Bright star of the atheist universe, 2011; MS138.001.003.00141; Wallace, Arminta (Box 3)
  - Take a vacation, 2012; MS138.001.003.00142; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Ye of Little Faith, 2012; MS138.001.003.00143; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Response to Fahrenfort and Lamme: defining reportability, accessibility and sufficiency in conscious awareness, 2012; MS138.001.003.00144; Cohen, Michael A.; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Four questions: Daniel C. Dennett on the most pervasive and serious threat religion poses to human rights, 2012; MS138.001.003.00145; Dey, Anouk (Box 3)
  - Sakes and dints: And other definitions that philosophers really need not seek, 2012; MS138.001.003.00146; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Science of Free Will and Other Matters: A Conversation with Daniel C. Dennett, 2012; MS138.001.003.00147; Shook, John (Box 3)
  - The Mystery of David Chalmers, 2012; MS138.001.003.00148; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - El alma está hecha de incontables y pequeñísimos robots, 2012; MS138.001.003.00149; Guillenea, Javier (Box 3)
  - Response to "The False Allure of Group Selection" by Steven Pinker, 2012; MS138.001.003.00150; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - A Perfect and Beautiful Machine': What Darwin's Theory of Evolution Reveals About Artificial Intelligence, 2012; MS138.001.003.00151; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Entry in Breakthrough!, 2012; MS138.001.003.00152; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Skeptic Interview with Professor Daniel Dennett, 2012; MS138.001.003.00153; Hyde, Deborah (Box 3)
  - Letter to Philosophy Now, 2012; MS138.001.003.00154; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett reviews Against Moral Responsibility by Bruce Waller, 2012; MS138.001.003.00155; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Erasmus: Sometimes a Spin Doctor is Right, 2012; MS138.001.003.00156; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The sleep of reason: do atheists improve the stock?, 2012; MS138.001.003.00157; McKay, Ryan; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Unimagined possibilities: Letter to Prospect Magazine, 2012; MS138.001.003.00158; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Kinds of Things--Towards a Bestiary of the Manifest Image, 2013; MS138.001.003.00159; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - He Saw Before Others, 2013; MS138.001.003.00160; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Why Some Sea Turtles Migrate, 2013; MS138.001.003.00161; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Expecting ourselves to expect: The Bayesian brain as a projector, 2013; MS138.001.003.00162; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Are criminals born or made?, 2013; MS138.001.003.00163; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - What is dreaming for, if anything?, 2013; MS138.001.003.00164; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Mounting disbelief, 2013; MS138.001.003.00165; Spencer, Nick (Box 3)
  - Philosophy That Stirs the Waters, 2013; MS138.001.003.00166; Schuessler, Jennifer (Box 3)
  - Interview with Dan Dennett, 2013; MS138.001.003.00167; Heaps, Chelsea (Box 3)
  - Dan Dennett Expects Smart Drugs, New Role for Churches, 2013; MS138.001.003.00168; Lundborg, Zinta (Box 3)
  - Thinking machine: an interview with Daniel Dennett, 2013; MS138.001.003.00169; Melville, Caspar (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett and Jesus Christ, 2013; MS138.001.003.00170; Spencer, Nick (Box 3)
  - The Philosopher's Self-Help Book (with Daniel Dennett), 2013; MS138.001.003.00171; Gots, Jason (Box 3)
  - Turing's Strange Inversion of Reasoning, 2013; MS138.001.003.00172; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Arching Voids and Making Voids: A review of Incomplete Nature: How Mind Emerged from Matter by Terrence W. Deacon, 2013; MS138.001.003.00173; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - An entry in The American Spectator, Books section, 2013; MS138.001.003.00174; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Kus Ma Olen?, 2013; MS138.001.003.00175; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The Evolution of Reasons, 2014; MS138.001.003.00176; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Artifactual selves: a response to Lynne Rudder Baker, 2014; MS138.001.003.00177; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Seduced by Tradition, 2014; MS138.001.003.00178; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Reflections on Free Will, 2014; MS138.001.003.00179; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Foreword to Richard Rorty: Mind, Language, and Metaphilosophy, 2014; MS138.001.003.00180; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Living without the Internet for a couple of weeks, 2014; MS138.001.003.00181; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Did HAL commit murder? / When HAL kills, who's to blame?, 2014; MS138.001.003.00182; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett interview in A Better Life, 2014; MS138.001.003.00183; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - If I ruled the world: Daniel Dennett, 2014; MS138.001.003.00184; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Daniel Dennett over de Schaakcomputer, 2014; MS138.001.003.00185; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Interview in Science and Religion: 5 Questions, 2014; MS138.001.003.00186; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - The software/wetware distinction: Comment on "Toward a computational framework for cognitive biology: Unifying approaches from cognitive neuroscience and comparative cognition" by W. Tecumseh Fitch, 2014; MS138.001.003.00187; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Filosoofia edeneb harva formaalsete argumentidega, 2014; MS138.001.003.00188; Mölder, Bruno (Box 3)
  - Ask a Philosopher: What Does New Brain Science Mean for Free Will?, 2014; MS138.001.003.00189; Goldberg, Carey (Box 3)
  - Dennett on Normativity, 2014; MS138.001.003.00190; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Commentary on Kamphorst and Kalis, 2014; MS138.001.003.00191; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 3)
  - Thank Goodness!, 2006-11-02; MS138.001.003.00192; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - The Part of Cognitive Science That Is Philosophy, 2009; MS138.001.003.00193; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Foreword to "Life Driven Purpose: How an Atheist Finds Meaning" by Dan Barker, 2015; MS138.001.003.00194; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Accession MS-2018-022
  - My Year at CASBS, 2015; MS138.001.003.00195; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - NYT Opinion: "Secularists: We're Fine Without God, Thanks", 2015; MS138.001.003.00196; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - What is the Bandwidth of Perceptual Experience?, 2015; MS138.001.003.00197; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Acession MS-2018-022
  - Freedom Evolves book jacket designs, 2003; MS138-040; 1.69 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 5 files.
    Closed due to copyright restrictions.
    electronic media
  - Publications, 1988 -- 2015; MS138-048; 9.53 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 16 files.
  - Publications, 2013 -- 2015; MS138-050; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.; 4.29 Megabytes
  - Publications, 2008 -- 2016; MS138-051; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.; 1.01 Megabytes
  - Publications, 2016; MS138-053; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 2 files.
  - Publications, 2015 -- 2016; MS138-054; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 5 files.; 2.1 Megabytes
- Additional accessions, 1970 -- 2017; MS138.002; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence - paper and electronic, writings and translations. The correspondence includes topics such as Dennett's books Consciouness Explained, Darwin's Dangerous Idea, and Freedom Evolves. There is also a manuscript for Intuition Pumps.
  This series is arranged in order of accession.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  - book in translation, MS138-031 (Box 34)
    Former barcode 39090014015453g
  - Unidentified Writings, MS138-033 (Box 35)
    This box contains unidentified fragments of writings and articles by Dennett, which were not processed in September 2010. Also included are the original tables of contents for the binders that originally housed Dennett's writings.
  - Consciousness Explained, MS138-035 (Box 36)
    Includes fan mail, follow up, reviews.
  - Darwin's dangerous idea, MS138-037 (Box 37)
    Closed until Dennett's death
    Includes follow up and fan mail, including battles with Steve Gould.
  - Freedom Evolves, MS138-038 (Box 38)
  - Freedom Evolves, MS138-039 (Box 39)
  - Publications, circa 2015 -- 2017; MS138.002.058; .022 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 24 PDFs.
    Open for mediated access due to copyright.
    Accession MS-2018-023
- Correspondence, circa 1970 -- 2017; MS138.003; 16.25 Linear Feet; 7 Digital Object(s)
  This series is closed until Dennett's death.
  This series contains Daniel Dennett's print and email correspondence.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1970's [1 of 2], 1970 -- 1979; MS138-005 (Box 1)
    Closed until Dennett's death.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1970's [2 of 2], 1970 -- 1979; MS138-006 (Box 2)
  - 1975-1982, 2 sets, 1 complete A-Z, 1 A-K [Correspondence], MS138-007 (Box 3)
  - 1975-1982 L-Z, MS138-008 (Box 4)
  - 1982-1985 A-G [Correspondence], MS138-009 (Box 5)
  - 1982-1985 H-Z [Correspondence], MS138-010 (Box 6)
  - 1985-1998 Correspondence, MS138-011 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1985 -- 1988; MS138-012 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1987 -- 1988; MS138-013 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1988 -- 1989; MS138-014 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1989 -- 1991; MS138-015 (Box 11)
  - FY 1991-1992 Correspondence, MS138-016 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1992 -- 1993; MS138-017 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence FY 1993-1994, MS138-018 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence FY 1994-1995, 1995-1996 [1 of 2, A-R], 1994 -- 1996; MS138-019 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence FY 1994-1995, 1995-1996 [2 of 2, S-Z], 1994 -- 1996; MS138-020 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1996 -- 1997; MS138-021 (Box 17)
  - Tufts Correspondence, 1997 -- 1998; MS138-022 (Box 18)
  - FY 1998/1999 Correspondence, MS138-023 (Box 19)
  - Fiscal Year Correspondence 1999-2000, MS138-024 (Box 20)
  - Fiscal Year Correspondence 2000-2001, MS138-025 (Box 21)
  - FY Correspondence 2001-2002, MS138-026 (Box 22)
  - Fiscal Year Correspondence July 2002-June 2003, 2002 -- 2003; MS138-027 (Box 23)
  - Fiscal Year Correspondence, 2003 -- 2004; MS138-028 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, FY2004, 2003 -- 2004; MS138.000770 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Transferred by Teresa Salvato, 2019, accession MS-2020-016.
  - Fiscal Year Correspondence, 2004 -- 2005; MS138-029 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence FY 2005-2006, French Transcript, 27 books in translation, 1985 -- 2006; MS138-030 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, FY 2006-2007, FY 2007-2008, and FY 2008-2009, 2006 -- 2008; MS138-032 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence regarding books and general correspondence fy2009-2010, 1984 -- 2010; MS138-034 (Box 28)
    Elbow Room; Brinchildren; The Intentional Stance; The Mind's I; Bradford Books = Brainstorms; Mind Movies BBC documentary on CONSCIOUSNESS EXPLAINED (Antenna).
  - Correspondence and drafts, MS138-036 (Box 29)